Munim Dibosh

Software Engineer

Dhaka, Bangladesh <u>abdulmunim.buet@gmail.com</u> | <u>http://dibosh.me/</u> +880 - 1946923667

I am a passionate programmer and love to learn new things. Experimenting with newest techs is one of my favourite pastimes. Have been involved in developing softwares for different platforms like mobile, desktop and web- nearly around 5 years now. My goal is to be a part of a team that works on a solution that eradicates at least one problem effectively for millions of lives.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Java - ObjectiveC - C/C++ - Python - Javascript

PLATFORMS & DEVELOPMENT PRACTICES

AngularJS - DJango - Flask - Android - iOS - SOA - OOP - Git

EXPERIENCE

NewsCred Inc, Dhaka Office - Full Stack Engineer (Full Time)

AUGUST 2014 - PRESENT

NewsCred is one of the leading content marketing solution providers. They provide Content Marketing software as a service.

- Currently Working on the core content ingestion engine solely developed in DJango
- Initially joined as Product Designer for one of the core teams and provided UX solutions along with front end development in AngularJS
- Was part of developing an interactive interface for original content clients to solicit ideas from their freelancers on top of MEAN stack
- Developed a content reporting dashboard used by sales team on top of AngularJS

ManGoesMobile, Dhaka - Software Engineer (20 hours a week)

NOVEMBER 2011 - JULY 2014

ManGoesMobile was a small startup founded by an ex-Googler focused to work on third world problems and building tools for them.

 Developed the Swinfen telemedicine system for doctors all over the world in both iOS and Android Designed and developed an interactive form creation and submission process for a group messaging application, in Android, using OpenDataKit

EDUCATION

Bangladesh University of Engineering & Technology, Dhaka

B.Sc in Computer Science & Engineering 2009 - 2014

Thesis - A mobile approach to find nearby bus stoppages in Dhaka, with optimal hop number to reach destination from a predefined source.

TOOLS & OTHERS

Project Management- Agile(Scrum), Jira

Design- Sketch, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

IDE- Eclipse, WebStorm, PyCharm, XCode

AWARDS

Certified Scrum Master

This is a certification from Scrum Alliance™ after a certain training program on Scrum and Agile methodologies. Certified persons are qualified to direct a Scrum team. Scored 29 out of 35.

Microsoft Imagine Cup, National Round, 4th Position

Microsoft Imagine Cup is considered to be the Olympic of Software Engineering contests. The certification is for securing 4th position among 114 teams in total, by developing an app for underprivileged children on top of .Net framework.